A Guide to the William E. Davis photographs, Series 1068 FA463
Rockefeller Archive Center
William E. Davis photographs, Series 1068
1956-1982
Rockefeller Archive Center
Davis, William E.
Rockefeller, Winthrop (1912-1973)
FA463
5.7 Cubic Feet 15 letter document boxes.
Approximately 593 contact sheets, 510 prints and associated negatives.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The William E. Davis photographs were donated to RAC by William E. Davis.
Biographical / Historical
William E. Davis served as a contract photographer for Winthrop Rockefeller and family.
Arrangement
Arranged in 3 subseries: 1. Winthrop Rockefeller, 2. Winrock, 3. Winthrop Paul Rockefeller. Within each subseries, the material is in original order, as received.
Scope and Contents
The William E. Davis photographs include portraits, candids and informal images of Winthrop Rockefeller and his immediate family, as well as Winthrop Paul Rockefeller and his immediate family. There is a small selection of images of conferences attended by Winthrop Rockefeller. The collection also contains extensive images of Winrock Farms including buildings, crops, employeees, parties, and cattle sales and receptions.
Photographs
- William E. Davis photographs, 1956-1982; 1068; 5.7 Cubic Feet 15 letter document boxes
  - Winthrop Rockefeller, 1
    - Arkansas Opportunity Fund Students, 5 contact sheets (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Conferences - Governor's Mansion, 3 contact sheets (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Conferences - Hot Springs, Arkansas with Duke Ellington (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Conferences - Regional, 10 contact sheets (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Conferences - Republican Governor's Conference with Ronald Reagan, 22 contact sheets (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
    - Conferences - Rural Planning, 3 contact sheets (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Conferences - Spiro Agnew at the Airport, 6 contact sheets (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Conferences - Spiro Agnew "We Will Do More for Arkansas", 8 contact sheets (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Family - Anne Bartley, Bruce Bartley, Marjorie Edris, 24 prints, 2 contact sheets (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Family - Jeannette Edris - Portraits, 2 prints (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Family - Wedding to Jeannette Edris, 1956; 8 prints (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Family - Winthrop Rockefeller and Jeannette Edris - Candids, 11 prints, 3 contact sheets (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Family - Winthrop and Winthrop Paul Rockefeller - Candids, 15 prints, 2 contact sheets (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Family Friends, 7 prints (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Family Friends - Winthrop Paul Rockefeller Friends, 14 contact sheets (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Parties - Christmas, 5 contact sheets (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Parties - "The People of Arkansas Thank You", 7 contact sheets (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Parties - Press Conference, 12 contact sheets (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Parties - Winrock Scholarship Recipients, 5 contact sheets (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Winthrop Rockefeller and Richard Nixon, 12 prints, 7 contact sheets (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Winthrop Rockefeller - Candids, 17 prints, 5 contact sheets (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Winthrop Rockefeller - Informals, 8 contact sheets (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Winthrop Rockefeller - Portraits, 46 prints, 6 contact sheets (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
    - Winthrop Rockefeller Series, Images 1-216. 17 contact sheets (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Winrock, 2
    - Arkansas Buildings, 3 contact sheets (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Winrock - Aerials, 43 prints, 9 contact sheets (Box 4, Folder 2-5)
    - Winrock - Buildings - Exteriors, 47 prints, 20 contact sheets (Box 4, Folder 6-8, Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Winrock - Buildings - Interiors, 18 prints, 2 contact sheets (Box 5, Folder 2-4)
    - Winrock - Cattle - In Fields, 8 contact sheets and negatives (Box 5, Folder 5-6)
    - Winrock - Cattle - In Pens, 13 prints, 6 contact sheets (Box 5, Folder 7-8, Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Winrock - Cattle - Sales and Receptions, 1960; 19 contact sheets, 1 print and negatives (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Winrock - Cattle - Sales and Receptions, circa 1965; 6 contact sheets and negatives (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Winrock - Cattle - Sales and Receptions, 1967; 3 contact sheets and negatives (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Winrock - Cattle - Sales and Receptions - "WR 13", circa 1970; 31 contact sheets and negatives (Box 6, Folder 5-6)
    - Winrock - Cattle - Sales and Receptions, 1976; 9 contact sheets and negatives (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Winrock - Cattle - Sales and Receptions, 1977; Negatives only (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Winrock - Employees - Candids, 31 contact sheets, 10 prints and negatives (Box 7, Folder 3-5, Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Winrock - Employees - Children, 1 contact sheet and negatives (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Winrock - Employees - Picnics, circa 1970; 3 contact sheets and negatives (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Winrock - Employees - Picnics, 1971; 5 contact sheets and negatives (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Winrock - Employees - Picnics, 1976; Negatives only (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Winrock - Employees - Picnics, 1977; Negatives only (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Winrock - Employees - Picnics, 1978; Negatives only (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Winrock - Employees - Portraits, 72 contact sheets and negatives (Box 8, Folder 8-9, Box 9, Folder 1-3)
    - Winrock - Farms - Grass, Negatives (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Winrock - Farms - Rice and Soybean, 23 contact sheets and negatives (Box 9, Folder 5, Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Winrock - Horses, 4 contact sheets and negatives (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Winrock - Objects, Approximately 50 prints and negatives (Box 10, Folder 3-5)
    - Winrock - Paintings - Objects, Negatives (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Winrock - Series A, 59 contact sheets and negatives (Box 11, Folder 1-6)
      Scope and Contents
      1-52
    - Winrock - Series B, 19 contact sheets and negatives (Box 11, Folder 7)
      Frames 1-239
  - Winthrop Paul Rockefeller, 3
    - Family - Children, 16 contact sheets, 50 prints, negatives (Box 12, Folder 1-3)
    - Family - Children - Andrea Rockefeller: Fourth Birthday, Negatives (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Family - Children - Winthrop Paul Rockefeller Jr. - Baptism, Negatives (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Family - Children, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 6-7)
    - Family - Children, 1982; 100 prints and negatives (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
    - Family - Deborah Cluett Sage Rockefeller, 1 contact sheet (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Family - Deborah Cluett Sage Rockefeller and Barbara Sears Rockefeller, 9 contact sheets and negatives (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Family - Series, 9 contact sheets and negatives (Box 13, Folder 5-7)
      1-30
    - Family - Wedding to Lisenne Dudderar, 3 prints and negatives (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Family - Winthrop Paul Rockefeller and Deborah Cluett Sage Rockefeller, 1971; 14 contact sheets, 4 prints and negatives (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Family - Winthrop Paul Rockefeller and Deborah Cluett Sage Rockefeller, 1973; 4 contact sheets, 18 prints and negatives (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Family - Candids, Negatives (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Family - Portraits, circa 1982; 13 contact sheets and negatives (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Parties - Arkansas Traveler Award, Negatives (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Parties - Arts Center, Negatives (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Parties - C.S.A. Awards, 1 contact sheet, negatives (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Parties - M.S. Meeting at Boat House, 1978; Negatives (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Parties - Ozark Folk Center, Negatives (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Parties - Reception with Henry Kissinger, 6 contact sheets (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Unidentified Lady, Negatives (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Winthrop Paul Rockefeller - Candids, 14 contact sheets and negatives (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Winthrop Paul Rockefeller - Portraits, 2 contact sheets and 11 prints (Box 15, Folder 9)